Preliminary Inventory to the Sergei L. Voitsekhovskii Papers, 1923-1982
Hoover Institution Archives
Sergei L. Voitsekhovskii Papers
1923-1982
79089
Hoover Institution Archives
11 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (5.6 linear feet)
Correspondence, memoranda, writings, printed matter, and photographs, relating to Russian history after 1917, Russians and Russian anti-communist movements in foreign countries, the Romanov dynasty, Soviet espionage within Russian emigre circles, and Grand Duke Vladimir Kirillovich
Voitsekhovskii, S. L. (Sergei L'vovich), 1900-
Access
Collection is open for research. The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1979.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical note
Russian historian.
Scope and Contents note
Correspondence, memoranda, writings, printed matter, and photographs, relating to Russian history after 1917, Russians and Russian anti-communist movements in foreign countries, the Romanov dynasty, Soviet espionage within Russian émigré circles, and Grand Duke Vladimir Kirillovich.
Kutepov, Aleksandr Pavlovich, 1882-1930.; Monarkhicheskoe Ob'edinenie Rossii.; Romanov, House of.; Vladimir Kirillovich, Grand Duke of Russia, 1917-; Anti-communist movements.; Communism.; Espionage, Russian.; Russia--Court and courtiers.; Russia.; Russians in foreign countries.; Soviet Union--History.; Soviet Union.; Subversive activities--Soviet Union.
- The Russian Orthodox Church Abroad, First Part (Box 1)
- George Artamanow, former delegate of the "Trust" and General Kutiepow in Poland
- "Soobshcheniia - Delo Borisa Savinkova," Istoriia SSSR, No., 6, 1967
- "Zarubezhnye Vysshie Voenno-Nauchnye Kursy Pod Rukovodstvom Professora General-Leitenanta N. N. Golovina, ", 1927-1977
- Armiia Obrechennykh, A. G. Aldan, Trudy Arkhiva Russkoi Osvoboditel'noi Armii, Tom 3, New York, 1969
- Prince George Shirinskii-Shikhmatov documents (Box 2)
- Prince T. K. Bagration-Murchanskii documents
- Grand Duke Vladimir Romanov documents (Box 2-3.)
- Richard Wraga correspondence and documents (Box 3)
- T. K. Bagration
- B. S. Browzin
- Jozef Mackiewicz
- Dr. Vera Piroschkow
- Professor Gleb Struve
- Russkoe Vozrozhdenie (Paris-Moscow-New York) (Box 4)
  - Nos. 1-4, 1978
  - Nos. 5-6, 1979
- The Russian Orthodox Church Abroad, The Goleniewski Case
- Ilia Glazunov and Dimitre Dudko
- The Eurasians, 1930-1933
- "The Voice of Emigrants," Nos. 1-8
- Zvezda, Leningrad, two articles by A. Saparov relating to enemies of communism in Russia, April-May 1972 (Box 5)
- Russian immigrants in Poland, 1932-1933
- Russian refugees in Austria and Germany occupied by the French Army, 1945-1950
- Suvorovets (Buenos Aires), 1954-1957 (Box 6)
- The Pilsudski Institute, New York
- The Pushkin Society, New York
- The Orthodox Church of America
- General Krasnow, executed in Moscow, 1951 July
- The Russian Imperial Alliance and Order
- George Jerebkoff, former assistant of General A. Vlasov
- Bohdan Kawecki, byly wiezien w in communist Russia
- Boris Brasol, Russian linguist
- "Novaia Imperiia," article, Russkii Demokrat (Paris), No. 1, 1950 (Box 7)
- German document, Berlin, relating to Russian monarchists, 1942 June
- German document, Berlin, relating to Russian immigrants in France, addressed to the Hauptstumfuhrer Brandenburg, 1942 June
- Soviet agents in Warsaw, 1923
- Philaret, Metropolitan, Conversation with, 1966 February 12
- Coats, Wendell J., letter, 1968 November
- Correspondence of Robert Samborski and Eugene Kerno, 1968
- Moskva, "The Remembrance of a Gestapo Judge,", 1971 June-August
- Russian Social Committee in Poland, 1930-1931
- Russian Social Committee in Poland, 1933-1937 (Box 8)
- Russian Social Committee in Poland, 1938-1940 (Box 9)
- Articles and reviews of S. Woyciechowski, 1926-1928
- Articles and reviews of S. Woyciechowski, 1929-1933 (Box 10)
- Russian emigre newspaper clippings, 1945-1952